EGOR PHILIPPOV

Senior Software Engineer

egor@philippov.ca • github.com/lone-cloud linkedin.com/in/egor-philippov • egor.philippov.ca

ABOUT

A passionate technology professional with the ability to work on all parts of an application, be it on the server, browser or mobile. Highly adaptable, innovative and articulate communicator specializing in building world class web applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PANASONIC REMOTE

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

APR 2020 - SEPT 2024

- Full stack development of <u>yohana.com</u> and <u>app.yohana.com</u> using Next.js (TypeScript + React + Node.js) and backend development of gRPC microservices using Micronaut (Kotlin). Implementation was based on collaboration with product and design teams mostly using Figma and Slack.
- Established and enforced best software development practices (strong typing, linting, spell checking, etc..), enforced strong accessibility guidelines, ran new candidate interviews, CI/CD implementation and general build + deployment automation using GitHub actions and TeamCity.
- Wrote and automated the re-publishing of a library for sharing the protobuf types between the services (Kotlin) and web (TypeScript) projects.
- Implemented rich, HTML-based, litmus-tested email templates and a related client library.
- Full stack development and prompt-engineering of AI-based research assistants using OpenAI's GPT-40 model with custom functions for real-time data fetching.

GOOGLE REMOTE & PALO ALTO, US

FULL STACK ENGINEER

OCT 2016 - Apr 2020

• Full stack development using Ember.js (JavaScript) and Golang. of various various enterprise applications for Google Store and Nest including enterprise.nest.com, hvac.nest.com and home.nest.com/login.

ABSOLUTE SOFTWARE

VANCOUVER, CANADA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

JAN 2014-Oct 2016

 Full stack development using Java EE and Ember.js of enterprise web applications for remote management of company owned mobile devices.

OPENBET TECHNOLOGIES

BURNABY, CANADA

JUNIOR - INTERMEDIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

AUG 2012 - Jan 2014

• Full stack development using TCL and Backbone.js for an online casino and sports betting portal for a Canadian casino at playnow.com.

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

VANCOUVER, CANADA

SEPT 2009 - Sept 2010

• Java development of installation software for a business intelligence suite (Crystal Reports).

EDUCATION

SAP

SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY